A Guide to the David Rockefeller papers, Associates, Leslie M. VanDerzee papers FA1231
Rockefeller Archive Center
David Rockefeller papers, Associates, Leslie M. VanDerzee papers
1960-1983
1973-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, David (1915-2017)
Van Derzee, Leslie
Rockefeller, Peggy
FA1231
4.94 Cubic Feet 13 letter document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted, in accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate, January 2019.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the correspondence and activities of Leslie M. VanDerzee in her capacity as an associate for David Rockefeller. The papers are primarily comprised of chronological files, contributions and pledges of David and Peggy Rockefeller, investment files, and a variety of projects and project proposals including those pertaining to land use and land management in New York, as well as a Rockwood Hall study center, and a brief history of the Rockefeller University Development Program.
- Rockefeller University Development Program - History and Present Status, 1977 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Office Projects, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Leslie M. VanDerzee Chronological File, 1977 November-1980 March (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Leslie M. VanDerzee Chronological File, 1980 April-1981 March (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Leslie M. VanDerzee Chronological File, 1981 April-1982 February (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- Leslie M. VanDerzee Chronological File, 1982 March-October (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
- Leslie M. VanDerzee Chronological File, 1982 November-1983 February (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- Jesuit Program for Living and Learning, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- J. Richardson Dilworth, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted - David Rockefeller Estate 1934 Trust - Open in 2027
- David Rockefeller - Contribution and Pledge Finance, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- David Rockefeller - Contributions-Pledges - General, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- David Rockefeller - General Philanthropic, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- David Rockefeller - Contributions, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
- Peggy Rockefeller - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Peggy Rockefeller - Contributions - Columbia County, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- David Rockefeller - Contributions, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 11, Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Board - American Works Project, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Confirmation Hearings, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
- Clivus Multrum, Inc. - Waste Management, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Museum of Primitive Art (MoPA) - Notes on Acquisition Policy, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Winthrop P. Rockefeller - Land Use Policy and Planning Act, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Alida D. Rockefeller - Use of Name other than Husband's Surname, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Fergus Reid III - Tax Shelter Opportunities, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Rockwood Hall Study Center, 1973 May-1974 October (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
- Rockwood Hall Study Center - Concept Development (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Rockwood Hall - Museums Visited, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Rockwood Hall Study Center, 1974 October-1976 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
- Rockwood Hall, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Rockwood Hall Study Center - Arthur W. Rashap File, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Land Use - Subdivision Regulations - Mt. Pleasant and New York Counties, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Land Use - Subdivision Regulations - New York State, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
- Miscellaneous Office Projects, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- William Wing Biographical Project (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Chase Manhattan Bank - Report of Relocation Task Force, c. 1970 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Investment Performance Analysis - Comparative Survey, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Winthrop Rockefeller Archives, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 6, Box 13, Folder 1-3)